Matthew Sawatzky

Winnipeg, MB | 204-226-3534 | matthewrsawatzky@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Full Stack Web Developer experienced in front-end design and back-end programming. Strong communicator able to clearly and concisely share ideas and work well with others. Well versed in UI/UX design to create engaging and unique user experiences in a variety of styles. Skilled in several languages and frameworks with a strong proficiency in TypeScript and React. Acquired a range of industry skills through formal education, work experience and multiple completed projects.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript; HTML/CSS, PHP; Java, Python, Ruby; SQL

Frameworks: React, Next.is, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap CSS, Rails, Flask

Tools: Docker, Postman, Git, Prisma, Microsoft Office

Cloud Services: AWS, Firebase, Supabase

WORK EXPERIENCE

BIZ BENEFITS

Winnipeg, MB

Full Stack Developer Intern

Aug 2024 - Present

- Developed for a nationwide business improvement area benefits company offering deals and services to a consumer base of businesses and employees
- Pushed website to production with my development team where it now is serving thousands of businesses and employees across Canada
- Built and maintained features using JavaScript, React and Next.js
- Secured and tested all API Endpoints ensuring full website and data security
- Implemented Prisma ORM to manage business and payment data
- Worked with Cron jobs to automate subscription renewals and notifications
- Improved UI/UX in key forms and deals page to better reflect the company's identity and professionalism
- Worked in a development team participating in agile sprints, stand-ups and code reviews
- Led and facilitated client meetings to align project outcomes with stakeholder expectations

FREELANCE WORK

Winnipeg, MB

BlueSky Fitness

Aug 2024 – Nov 2024

- Created a TypeScript-based landing page utilizing react for a local fitness studio
- Developed a responsive and user-friendly fitness website to provide users with a comprehensive idea of the classes, personal training and benefits the studio offers
- Designed the website with a clean and straightforward layout to cater to an older client demographic, ensuring gym information was accessible and prominently displayed
- Worked closely with the client to meet their specific needs and requirements
- Implemented Tailwind CSS to create a cohesive and visually appealing website experience
- Enhanced the user experience while maintaining simplicity through adding smooth animations to key elements creating an engaging and dynamic interface

EDUCATION

RED RIVER COLLEGE POLYTECHNIC

Full Stack Web Development

Winnipeg, MB

Aug 2023 - Sep 2024

Full Stack Web Development Diploma

Cumulative GPA: 3.8;

Relevant Coursework: Front-End Development, Back-End Development, Programming, Agile Development; Database Management, Web Security; Object-Oriented Design, Project Management, Business Requirements, IT Foundations; Communications

Certifications & Training: AWS Academy Cloud Foundations certificate, Udemy React training, Udemy Next.js training